Hello again. So, here I'm going to be showing you how to actually build this network,
又见面了 现在我来讲怎么创建这个网络
so go through the inputs and the embedding layer and the soft max.
我们会讲到输入、嵌入层和 softmax 层
So, as usual, we have our tensor flow placeholders,
和之前一样 用 TensorFlow 的占位符函数  tf.placeholder
so we're using integers in both of these and so just tf.n32 and then
这两个占位符都要用整数 也就是 tf.n32
the labels have arbitrary batch size and arbitrary second dimension.
还要用批大小和第二维度都随机的标签
So the deal is like with inputs and labels,
所以在处理输入和标签时
for both of them we're actually just passing in like just integers and so,
实际我们要传递的就是整数
you know, when I first started doing this,
当我第一次做这件事时
when I first built this, like,
也就是当我第一次创建这个网络时
I thought I could just have them both like this.
我以为两个都可以这么写
But then later when I was trying to implement part of the network,
但之后当我在实现网络的某个部分时
I kept having issues with the labels needing to have a second dimension.
那些需要第二维度的标签总是会出错
So it's just sort of one of those things when
这种情况还挺常见的
you build it and you think you can just do one thing,
创建时你以为只需做一件事
then as you go through it you start hitting bugs and then you have to kind of go back
可随着你不断深入 你发现漏洞层出不穷
and change the earlier part
所以你不得不回到前面
of your network to get it to work with the later part of your network.
修改网络 从而解决网络后面出现的问题
Okay. So now the embedding.
好了 然后是嵌入层
So I set the embedding dimensions to 200 and then for our embedding weights
把嵌入维数设为 200 为了设置嵌入权重
I create a variable and use a random uniform distribution and the size of this,
我创建了个变量 使用随机均匀分布的函数 random_uniform
this weight tensor is going to
权重张量的大小
be the size of our vocabulary by the size of the embedding.
则是词汇量大小与嵌入层大小的乘积
And then I just initialized it from -1 to 1.
然后将范围初始化为 -1 到 1
And then to do the embedding look up,
然后做嵌入查询表
so just tf.nnembedding_lookup and then embedding and inputs.
所以就这么写 tf.nn.embedding_lookup 然后是嵌入和输入
So this will give you your embed tensor and this is basically just,
这样你就得到了嵌入张量
you know, the values of the hidden layer.
其实就是隐藏层的值
So, in general, you are going to be doing the same process,
总地来说 使用嵌入
like anytime you're using embeddings.
要进行的操作都是一样的
So you create your embedding matrix and then you pass in your inputs into
创建嵌入矩阵 将输入传递给嵌入矩阵
the embedding matrix and you get
从而得到这个嵌入层
this embed layer and then you can pass this to the rest of your network.
然后你就可以把嵌入层传递给网络了
Okay. And finally for the negative sampling,
好了 最后是负采样
so again create weights and biases for the soft max layer.
还是为 softmax 层创建权重和偏置
So we're initializing the weights with the truncated normal distribution.
用截断正态分布函数 truncated_normal 把权重初始化
And so this is going to be,
所以
we need the weights to be the size of vocabulary and the size of the embedding.
定义权重大小为词汇量的大小和嵌入层的大小
And then we have a standard deviation of 0.1.
标准差设为 0.1
And the biases are going to be initialized as all zeros with the size of our vocabulary.
偏置全部初始化为 0 大小是词汇量的大小
So now to actually calculate the loss with
要用负采样计算损失
negative sampling we used sampled Softmax loss,
我们要用函数 sampled_softmax_loss
passing our weights or biases,
要传递给函数的参数有权重、偏置、
the labels are an embedding layer and then the, in the sampled.
标签、嵌入层、n_sampled
So this is like the number of negative values that we're going to
n_sampled 是们要采样的负样本数
sample and then the size of
然后是词汇量的大小
our vocabulary and that will run in this negative sampling and calculator loss.
运行这个负采样 计算损失
And then we get the cost and minimize it with Adam optimizer.
得到损失 用 AdamOptimizer 将其最小化